Farhana Shahid



✓ farhana.shahid@bracu.ac.bd

https://farhana-shahid.github.io/

Research Interests

My research interests encompass the diverse spectra of Human-Computer Interaction, Ubiquitous Computing, and Social Computing. I have broad interests in the design, use, and social impact of technologies that create sustainable outcomes for low-resource communities.

Appointments

May 2018 - Present

Lecturer. Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Brac University Dhaka, Bangladesh.

Sep 2017 - Apr 2018

Lecturer. Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Eastern University Dhaka, Bangladesh.

Education

2017 - 2019

M.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering

Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology Advisor: A. B. M. Alim Al Islam

GPA: 4.00 out of 4.00

2013 - 2017

B.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering

Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology

Advisor: A. B. M. Alim Al Islam

GPA: 3.74 out of 4.00

Research Publications

Journal Publications

1 Farhana Shahid, Wasifur Rahman, M. Saifur Rahman, Sharmin Akther Purabi, Ayesha Seddiqa, Moin Mostakim, Farhan Feroz, Tanjir Rashid Soron, Fahmida Hossain, Nabila Khan, Anika Binte Islam, Nipi Paul, Ehsan Hoque, and A. B. M. Alim Al Islam. 2020. Leveraging Free-Hand Sketches for Potential Screening of PTSD. In Proceedings of the ACM on Interactive Mobile, Wearable and Ubiquitous Technologies (IMWUT' 20). Vol. 4, No. 3, Article 94 (September 2020), 22 pages.

2 Farhana Shahid, Shahinul Hoque Ony, Takrim Rahman Albi, Sriram Chellappan, Aditya Vashistha, and A. B. M. Alim Al Islam. 2020. Learning from Tweets: Opportunities and Challenges to Inform Policy Making During Dengue Epidemic. In Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction. Vol. 4, Issue CSCW1, Article 65 (May 2020), 27 pages. **Y CSCW Honorable Mention Award (Top 5%)**

3 Farhana Shahid, Wasifur Rahman, Anika Binte Islam, Nipi Paul, Nabila Khan, Mohammad Saifur Rahman, Md Munirul Haque, and A. B. M. Alim Al Islam. 2019. Two Tell-tale Perspectives of PTSD: Neurobiological Abnormalities and Bayesian Regulatory Network of the Underlying Disorder in a Refugee Context. In Proceedings of the ACM on Interactive Mobile, Wearable and Ubiquitous Technologies (IMWUT' 19). Vol. 3, No. 3, Article 101 (September 2019), 45 pages. **TIMWUT Distinguished Paper Award**

Academic Awards

Distinguished Paper Award, IMWUT Volume 3. 2020

Honorable Mention Award, CSCW2020.

■ University Merit Scholarship, Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology. 2016

Dean's List Award, Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology. 2015

Academic Awards (continued)

- **First Runner Up: Poster Presentation**, Esonance, Islamic University of Technology.
- 2012 Champion: Science Olympiad, Inter College Science Festival, Holy Cross College.
- First Runner Up, 4th Bangladesh Chemistry Olympiad.
 - Secondary School Merit Scholarship, Education Board of Dhaka.

Teaching Experience

Course Instructor

- Computer Graphics (Fall 2020, Summer 2020, Spring 2020, Fall 2019, Summer 2019, Spring 2019, Spring 2018)
- Pattern Recognition (Fall 2020, Summer 2020)
- Artificial Intelligence (Spring 2020, Fall 2019)
- Object Oriented Programming (Fall 2019, Summer 2019, Spring 2019, Fall 2018, Summer 2018)
- Digital Logic Design (Spring 2020, Summer 2018)
- Algorithms (Summer 2019, Fall 2019, Summer 2018)
- Data Structures (Summer 2019, Summer 2018)
- Operating Systems (Spring 2018, Fall 2017)
- Mathematical Analysis for Computer Science (Fall 2017)

Course Coordinator

- Pattern Recognition (Fall 2020, Summer 2020)
- Computer Graphics (Fall 2020, Spring 2020, Fall 2019)
- Artificial Intelligence (Summer 2020, Spring 2020, Fall 2019)
- Object Oriented Programming (Fall 2020, Fall 2019)

Mentoring

Undergraduate Students

- Takrim Rahman Albi
- Shahinul Hoque Ony

Service

University Service

2019–2020 AI, ML, and NLP thesis panel, Brac University.

2019 Course curriculum update, Brac University.

2018 Semester planning, Brac University.

Organizing Committee

2017 | 5th Eastern University Math Olympiad, Eastern University.

National High School Programming Contest, BUET.

Reviewer

2021 ACM Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI).

2020 Asian CHI Symposium.

Selected Talks

Conference Talks

Oct 2020 Learning from Tweets: Opportunities and Challenges to Inform Policy Making During Dengue Epidemic, CSCW 2020.

Sep 2020 Leveraging Free-Hand Sketches for Potential Screening of PTSD, UbiComp 2020.